# **Francis Kim**

\_

**Software Developer** 

francis.kim@yale.edu (859)494-0978 francis-m-kim.github.io LinkedIn · GitHub

#### **Projects**

\_

#### **Skills**

Ruby, Rails, SQL, jQuery, JavaScript, Node.js, React.js, Git, HTML5, CSS, MaxMSP, Processing, Autodesk Maya, Adobe Photoshop **Cruddyreads:** A full stack web app inspired by Goodreads, built with Rails and React.

- Permits Twitter login through OmniAuth for a seamless user experience.
- Uses AWS3 to store images. Remote hosting in the cloud allows for future scalability.
- React lifecycle methods and Flux architecture ensure that application data and rendering are in sync.

**Quindici:** A browser game inspired by the classic Game of 15 puzzle, using an image or GIF background.

- All aspects of the game are customizable: board dimensions, difficulty, and background can all be changed by the user.
- Uses jQuery listeners and CSS hover-overs to respond to user interaction and change game state.
- Leverages image-caching to optimize load times for multiple instances of the same image.
- Employs a custom algorithm to ensure that the game begins only with winnable tile positions.

myQuery: A lightweight JavaScript library for DOM manipulation

- Common DOM tasks like adding or modifying HTML are simplified by wrapping elements in a JavaScript object which abstracts away mundane complexities.
- With a focus on modularity and code reuse, the library weighs in at less than 10 kilobytes, so as not to affect page load time.

## Education

## App Academy, 2016

12-week full-stack development bootcamp with < 5% acceptance rate

Yale University School of Music, M.M., Organ Performance, GPA: 3.85, 2013-15

- · Recipient of Full Merit Scholarship and Fellowship
- Recipient of Charles Ives Prize for Organ

Catholic University of America, Graduate studies in Philosophy, 2007–08

University of Louisville, B.A., Philosophy, GPA: 3.65, 2005–07

**Oberlin College Conservatory of Music, Piano Performance**, 2002-05

Recipient of Conservatory Dean's Scholarship

## **Experience**

**Associate Music Director at St. Pius X Church, Scarsdale, NY**, 2015–16 Directed the choir and played organ for a congregation of > 1,000. Taught music lessons to parish children.

Instructor at the Yale School of Music, New Haven, CT, 2013-15

Taught weekly organ lessons to Yale students. Students received school credit for their lessons.

**Director of Music at St. Stephen Martyr Church, Washington, DC**, 2010–12 Played organ for all services and conducted a choir of 8 paid singers. Led the process of hiring new singers.